<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on C-MOOR</title>
    <link>/resource/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on C-MOOR</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/resource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resource/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/intro/</guid>
      <description>Scroll down or click on any of these topics to see suggested resources for learning more:
 Biology Next Generation Sequencing RNA-seq Statistics Machine Learning R  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biology</title>
      <link>/resource/biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/biology/</guid>
      <description>Crash Course has several videos explaining biology concepts. We recommend the following videos in particular if you&amp;rsquo;d like to work on sequence analysis:
 Animal Cells Biological Molecules DNA structure Transcription and Translation  Some additional videos on genes and genomes:
 Harvard, “An Introduction to the Human Genome” Scientific American, “Genes vs. DNA vs. Chromosomes”  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Generation Sequencing</title>
      <link>/resource/next-gen-sequencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/next-gen-sequencing/</guid>
      <description>  Rafa Irizarry, &amp;ldquo;Intro to Next Generation Sequencing” Ben Langmead, “Intro to Alignment” Visualizing genomic data with IGV NCBI, &amp;ldquo;The FASTQ File Format&amp;rdquo;: A common, standard format for sequencing data  Sequencing Technologies: The following videos give an overview of the technical process of different modern sequencing strategies
 Illumina: Short reads, high accuracy, high throughput Nanopore: Very long reads, lower accuracy, moderate throughput Sanger: Long reads, high accuracy, very low throughput  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA-seq</title>
      <link>/resource/rnaseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/rnaseq/</guid>
      <description>Introductory videos  Rafa Irizarry, “Intro to RNA-seq” (5 min) Kasper Hansen, “Introduction to RNAseq” (1 hr 17 min)  Online texts  RNA-seqlopedia: &amp;ldquo;The RNA-seqlopedia provides an overview of RNA-seq and of the choices necessary to carry out a successful RNA-seq experiment.&amp;rdquo; It provides a good background and overview but does not go into the practical details of how to do the various data analysis steps (what programs to use and how to use them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics</title>
      <link>/resource/statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/statistics/</guid>
      <description> Videos  StatQuest: A collection of videos explaining a variety of statistics concepts and methods. Rafa Irizarry, &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Statistics&amp;rdquo;  Online textbooks  Modern Statistics for Modern Biology Statistical Modeling: A Fresh Approach  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/resource/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description> The Elements of Statistical Learning Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition fast.ai Google AI  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/resource/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/r/</guid>
      <description>R for Data Science &amp;ldquo;This book will teach you how to do data science with R: You’ll learn how to get your data into R, get it into the most useful structure, transform it, visualise it and model it.&amp;rdquo; swirl: &amp;ldquo;swirl teaches you R programming and data science interactively, at your own pace, and right in the R console!&amp;rdquo; DataCamp Introduction to R: &amp;ldquo;In this introduction to R, you will master the basics of this beautiful open source language, including factors, lists and data frames.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>